Phạm Thành Khang Software Developer



Ha Noi, Viet Nam // (+84) 965 184 529 // khangtpc@gmail.com // Portfolio

PROFILE

Motivated and resourceful Software Developer with more than 3 years of experience, driven by a passion for coding, programming, and creating powerful software solutions. Possessing an in-depth understanding of C#, .NET, VB, Cloud Computing, and SQL, as well as knowledge of emerging technologies, best practices and user experience standards. Aiming to contribute specialized software engineering expertise to a dynamic organization to enable high levels of productivity and customer satisfaction.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Rikkeisoft

Security Price Management Project

Middle Software Developer // June 2024 - Present

- Collaborate, support and working with cross-region teams (India, London) to develop and implement financial software solutions for Western market client.
- Developed and optimized SQL Server solutions, including designed and maintained complex stored procedures, views, and functions for financial data management.
- Built and maintained SSIS packages cooperate with Control-M job for ETL processes, automating data extraction, transformation, and loading from multiple sources.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to developed C# .NET-based applications, modules and services, enhancing business operations with scalable and efficient solutions.
- Provided CI/CD strategies using GitHub Actions and Azure Pipelines as automating build, test, and deployment workflows.
- Utilized Git and Jira for version control and agile project management, ensuring seamless collaboration and deployment.

FPT SoftWare

Migration Project for Storage Management System Junior Software Developer // June 2023 - May 2024

- Small team leader of 5 developer in a project regarding migrating and developing new multi-app WinForms system utilizing C# and .NET Framework with Visual Basic.
- Configured and managed Oracle and SQL Server databases.

- Provided and managed data for testing and production environments.
- Established and maintained development and testing environments for the project.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to gather requirements and provide technical guidance.

AWS Cloud Monolith to Microservices E-Commerce

Junior Software Developer // September 2023 – January 2024

- Performed transitioning a C# .NET monolithic backend application to microservices architecture.
- Build out a CI/CD process that triggered with Git commit to automatically builds and deploys Docker images into a Kubernetes cluster.
- Develop a system consists of serverless REST APIs using API Gateway and AWS Lambda, data storage with DynamoDB, AWS S3 and AWS CloudFormation for application resources utilizing.

Memory Leakage Prevention Project

Fresher Software Developer // January 2023 - April 2023

• Conduct performance evaluation, logic bug detection, thorough dead code analysis and potential memory leakage risks assessment for a C/C++ based system across Windows and Linux based operating systems.

Hanoi University of Science and Technology

Electric Battery Simulation for Electric Vehicle

Associate Researcher // May 2022 - January 2023

 Hands-on experience with Software Development using C/C++, Python and Matlab for simulation of electric batteries in associated industrial collaborations as well as graduated projects.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING

School of Electrical Engineering // Ha Noi University of Science and Technology **2018 - 2023**

AWS CLOUD DEVELOPER CERTIFICATION

Udacity – FPT Software

2023

SKILLS + KNOWLEDGE

Language & Framework

C# // Visual Basic // .Net // C/C++ // Typescript // React // Bootstrap // SQL

Databases & ETL

Relational Database (SQL Server, Oracle, ...) // NoSQL (MongoDB) // Query Optimization // Database Design // SSIS // ETL Design Patterns

DevOps

GitHub Actions // Azure DevOps // AWS // Docker // Kubernetes

Other Tools & Soft Skills

Git // Jira // AWS // Problem Solving // Advanced English // Communication